

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER · DEVELOPER ADVOCATE

💌 joey.mckenzie27@gmail.com | 🌴 joeymckenzie.tech | 🖸 JoeyMcKenzie | 🛅 JoeyMcKenzie | 💆 @_joeyMcKenzie | 🗑 the_beercoder

Summary_

Seasoned professional software developer with diverse experience building enterprise-grade distributed software systems with technologies in .NET, Java, and TypeScript across industries including healthcare, insurance, manufacturing, and fintech. I specialize in building fast, efficient cloud-based web services and APIs with AWS and Azure alongside modern web applications with Angular, React, and Vue. I have a passion for software architecture and design, software leadership and mentorship, and delivering high-quality software products at a nationwide scale.

I am an avid contributor to open source, primarily in the **Rust** and **TypeScript** ecosystems, alongside minor contributions in **Go** with community projects hosted across **GitHub**, **Vercel** and **Netlify**. I enjoy dispersing knowledge and experience with other like-minded developers sharing a similar passion for software development and design. I write and produce technical content on my blog, Twitch, and YouTube exploring emerging technologies with a focus on developer advocacy.

Experience

National Funding Remote

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2022 - Present

- Developing .NET microservices, React applications with Next.js, and AWS infrastructure supporting financial operations
- Migrating legacy services to serverless architectures with AWS Lambda, EventBridge, S3, and SQS
- Integrating external financial partner APIs into backend systems, increasing customer lending conversion by up to 40%
- · Managing CI/CD pipelines and automated processes with AWS, Terraform, Jenkins, and containerized workflows with Docker
- Upgrading internal .NET infrastructure improving performance and speed by 25% while reducing AWS costs
- Troubleshooting applications errors using log aggregation services with **OpenSearch** and **Kibana**
- Maintaining company-wide build artifacts with NuGet and source code with GitHub
- Leading company-wide modernization efforts to develop publicly available APIs for consumers in the fintech space

MediKeeper Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Dec. 2020 - Jan. 2022

- Developed .NET and JavaScript applications with Vue deployed to Azure infrastructure
- · Worked with product teams and UX designers to compose Sass and Material Design-based UIs with Figma
- Migrated existing CI/CD pipelines and automated processes to Azure DevOps to improve existing build times
- Administered SQL Server and Oracle databases while improving business critical query times by up to 35%
- Improved existing system architecture by migrating legacy .NET Framework applications to modern .NET
- · Maintained integration suites with JavaScript and Cypress to automate platform testing, increasing QA velocity by 20%

Sierra Pacific Industries Redding, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jan. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- Developed internal applications and dashboards using modern RPG ILE on the IBM iSeries AS/400 and .NET for desktop applications
- Migrated brownfield and legacy applications to modern RPG architectures increasing application response times
- Improved business critical PL/SQL queries for embedded systems by up to 40% in several applications
- Maintained company-wide build artifacts with RDi, Azure DevOps, and VSTS
- Managed database schemas with SQL Server using SSMS to support inventory management operations

VSP Global Sacramento, CA
ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER
Jun. 2018 - Jan. 2020

• Developed Java APIs and Angular applications with TypeScript deployed to AWS hosting infrastructure

- Migrated legacy **JEE** and **Spring** applications to **Spring Boot** while increasing response times by up to 25%
- Lead development of Angular applications utilizing Material Design, Sass, RxJS, NgRx, and modern web standards
- · Created and maintained CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins, Chef, and containterized workflows with Docker
- Administrated systems and servers while migrating non-production workloads off legacy **Windows** servers to **Linux** servers
- Maintained company-wide build artifacts with Artifcatory and source code with BitBucket
- Assisted in troubleshooting company-wide service outages and application performance issues with Splunk and Wily

Engility Corporation San Diego, CA

OPERATIONS RESEARCH ANALYST

• Wrote and maintained VBA and R codebases to perform data analysis and spreadsheet specific functionality

- Provided contractor support for U.S. Department of Defense naval programs for systems engineering and data analysis
- Performed regression analysis and statistical programming using R to refine estimated financial expenditure models
- Managed automated **Excel** spreadsheets and codebases in **RStudio** for data analysis and exploration
- · Maintained databases of financial data and provided ad hoc SQL reporting for various projects

Education

San Diego State University

San Diego, CA

Sept. 2016 - May 2018